= www.kisskh.asia =
SAY NO TO PIRACY, SUPPORT ORIGINALS
ADAPTED FROM THE ORIGINAL WEB NOVEL
THE EARLY SPRING, BY GU NIANG BIE KU
What would you have said?
And back then, I was craving
my dad's braised fish.
Do not halt the project.
Make sure everything is in order.
I'll rush back now.
Dad.
I feel cold.
I have work to do.
Your mom will be here later.
Call the nurse if you need anything.
FOLLOW ME HOME
You didn't have to come to work this soon.
Running around won't do
your recovery any good.
Your arm hasn't healed yet,
and you are driving.
I use my hands to steer, not my arms.
Shang Zhitao.
At work, courtesy is redundant.
It's all about an air of gravitas.
If your opponent knows you're a pushover,
you'll be swallowed whole.
Noted. Thank you.
Didn't I tell you to stop
thanking someone easily?
Have you forgotten?
I'll bear that in mind, Luke.
Are you not going to ask
where we are going?
Aren't you afraid I'll sell you out?
I owe my life to you.
Whatever it is, it's my treat.
I owe my life to you too.
How do you want me to repay it?
I hate owing someone a favor.
Let's just pretend
it's just you who owes me a favor.
Then, how do you want me to repay you?
Slowly.
This… This is a restaurant?
Are you afraid I'll dump your body
in the wilderness?
BE BACK SOON
Mian is waiting for you.
Let's go in.
Okay.
BE BACK SOON
Over here.
Careful.
Thanks.
Didn't you say
you were craving braised fish?
Which one do you want? Catch it yourself.
You must be the smart student
who doesn't need to study hard
to get first place in your examinations.
Do you truly think
smart students never study?
I used to think hard work would pay off,
but I don't think so anymore.
How's the catch?
Did you get any fish?
Tan Mian.
Owner of this private restaurant.
Also an advertisement veteran
who knows how to cook the best.
Thank you.
Shang Zhitao.
- Hi, Ms. Shang.
- Hi.
All right. Stop fishing. It's tedious.
Ms. Shang. Which one do you want?
I brought a net to scoop it up for you.
Teaching one to fish
is better than giving them a fish.
Yes. I want to catch one myself.
Luke, thanks for teaching me how to fish.
I now understand that
not only do I have to work hard,
but I have to seize the right timing too.
I didn't teach you anything.
You learned it yourself.
The food is ready.
Try it.
My secret grilled fish.
Thank you.
Girlfriend?
No.
Luke and I are colleagues.
Does she look like my girlfriend at all?
Right.
Then, this colleague of yours
must be more important than a girlfriend.
You are serving her personally.
Focus when you're eating fish.
Enjoy it.
- It's nice.
- Right?
The fish you caught
will always taste good.
If you know how to use bait,
you won't find yourself lacking in fish.
Yes. We should always learn from Luke
so that we don't become idiots.
You hold grudges.
Ms. Shang.
I have a question.
What do you think
is Luke's biggest talent?
His creativity.
Everyone says Luke
is a prodigy in the advertising industry
that you can't find elsewhere.
Prodigy?
Ten years ago, I thought so too.
I thought one good slogan
could leverage the entire Pacific Ocean.
But you can generate
as much hype as you want.
If your client's products
are not sold out,
they won't give you the budget
to support your vision.
See, Ms. Shang?
His biggest talent is not creativity,
but nitpicking.
When he nitpicks,
his words are more precise than a slogan.
Dig in.
It's probably a circuit breaker trip.
Just eat. Let me check on it.
How did you come in?
You pried the lock open?
Mr. Tan.
Where is Luan Nian?
Luan Nian?
I told you he and I are no longer friends.
We have closed. Just leave.
How many drinks did you have?
- I'll hail a taxi to get you home.
- I heard someone talking inside.
- Hey you…
- You're lying to me!
Why would I lie to you?
Luan Nian is inside. I know it.
- Luan Nian!
- No, he isn't.
- It's my other friend.
- Listen. You're there, aren't you?
Luan Nian isn't here.
If you lie to me,
I'll burn your restaurant.
Burn my restaurant?
That's a crime, miss.
Do you know
how much jail time you will get?
Stop taking me for a fool.
- Luan Nian! I know you're in there.
- He isn't here.
- Don't ignore me. Come out.
- Just leave.
- Luan Nian! Luan Nian!
- Go.
- Careful.
- He isn't here.
Just go.
- Luan Nian!
- Careful.
- Don't worry.
- Don't ignore me.
Come out now!
Just let me see you. We need to talk.
Luan Nian!
- I won't leave unless you come out.
- What happened?
- Luan Nian!
- Something came up.
Let's call it a day now.
- Luan Nian.
- After she leaves,
I'll drive you back.
Okay.
Luan Nian.
I finally get to see you.
I'm begging you.
Let's get back together.
I won't be what I was before.
I'll change.
Zhang Xin.
We already broke up.
You need to accept the truth.
There's no point in holding
onto this any longer.
No point?
For you, I argued with my parents,
gave up everything I had in the US,
and returned to Beijing.
- Is that nothing in your eyes?
- You made the decision yourself.
Don't pin that on me.
We both chose to break up.
It's been a year.
You've been texting, calling,
and stalking me.
Enough is enough.
It's time to put an end to this.
I am having a private moment
with my friend.
Please leave.
Your friend?
Don't deny it.
She's your new love interest.
Relationships go through ups and downs.
We broke up.
So, I'll just wait
until you break up with her.
When did you two get together?
You misunderstood.
We're just co-workers.
This is between us.
Do not involve other people.
Go inside first.
- Don't come near me!
- Zhang Xin.
- Don't come near me.
- Drop it.
Calm down.
Don't do anything reckless.
Put the knife down now.
Leave this place.
I'll pretend nothing happened here.
I already called the police.
I love you so much.
Yet you go and love someone else.
Calm down. Put the knife down.
You know what? Let's talk. Okay?
Tell me.
What did I do wrong?
I think you need treatment.
I'll go with you to see a therapist.
No.
You used to call me a control freak.
You think I'm sick, don't you?
- You think I'm crazy?
- No, I do not.
But you cannot
let this obsession continue.
Give me the knife.
- Are you okay, Luan Nian?
- Are you out of your mind?
‪Luan Nian…
I'm fine.
- I…
- Again?
Are you okay?
Stop her.
Ms. Shang.
- You must have been terrified.
- No.
Please don't misunderstand.
They only dated briefly,
and they broke up a long time ago.
I can reassure you
that Luke would never two-time anyone.
No, you have the wrong idea.
We really are just colleagues.
He's my superior.
Then, you're the first co-worker
he brought to my restaurant.
That's because he has helped me a lot.
I wanted to buy him a meal to thank him.
Perhaps you didn't know
that Luke and I were co-workers once too.
In one year, I closed deals
worth 80 million yuan.
Yet he never bought me dinner.
Did you use to work in Lime too?
No.
Luke and I worked together
before he went to Lime.
He used to own
his own advertising company.
I worked under him.
Why did you two quit then?
We lost the drive.
In all those years,
we encountered many unreasonable clients.
Every day, our work could not be finished.
People couldn't be reasoned with.
They blew hot and cold.
And we spent every day carrying out
useless communication.
I quit. I was tired.
Why didn't he continue then?
Do not ever mention
his company before him.
He'll scowl at you.
We were betrayed by one of our own.
Luke was seriously affected by it.
Besides, his family prohibited him
from starting his own business.
What were you guys talking about?
How's your hand?
I'm fine.
The doctor said not to wet the wound.
Be mindful of that.
I'll leave you two be then.
I'll bring the car over.
Come. We'll drive you home.
I already hailed a taxi.
You two are leaving now?
Are you not going to look after her?
Why should I?
I already informed her family.
You must think
I'm an irresponsible playboy.
No.
Relationships can be messy
and complicated.
Worry not.
I won't tell anyone. I swear.
I do not believe in vows.
And I don't care about others' opinions.
She and I already broke up.
When two people first get together,
I think they often share the same goal.
But as time goes by,
people might change their minds.
It's no one's fault
if the relationship falls apart.
People want different things, that's all.
She chose to hold onto it,
and you chose to let go.
There's no right or wrong.
So you're saying
I should keep entangling with her,
even though I no longer love her.
No, I didn't say that.
I just think that love shouldn't
make one this miserable.
How many relationships have you had?
Just one.
How was the breakup?
A reluctant separation
with mutual blessings?
We had good intentions
when we got together,
and we didn't break up unhappily.
You're quite mature when it comes to love.
I… I think my taxi is here.
Let me check.
Tao.
How come you're back?
Want to hang out tonight?
I can't.
I need to brush up on my English.
My colleagues all studied abroad.
I don't want to fall too far behind.
- You go ahead.
- You stay at home all the time.
You've been studying every day
during your days off.
You're affecting my after-work life.
All of you are here.
You should go out and relax.
It's Friday today.
I'm dumb, so I have to work harder.
Oh. My friends invited me to play the game
Legends of the Three Kingdoms later.
Do you want to join us?
What did I just say?
Friday is meant for fun.
LTK or the bar.
Pick one.
Neither.
Talk some sense into her.
Oh. I fixed this one. Take this.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Stop hesitating, Tao.
Sun's friends must be very smart.
Let's go meet some quality people.
It's just studying
in a different place, right?
So that's a deal then. I'll get changed.
Hurry up.
I changed my mind. I'll wear this.
It's pretty.
- Let me check on my cards.
- That's rough, buddy.
Wait, how does "Kill" work?
- Can I just use "Dodge" to get out of it?
- Hello!
- It's rare that Sun is willing to come out
- Hello.
and he brought
two beautiful girls with him.
Introduce them to us.
I am Sun Yu.
You can call me Yu or Dabaoyu.
Hello.
This is Tao.
- Shang Zhitao.
- Hello.
- Take a seat.
- Come.
- The drinks are here.
- Careful.
- Thanks.
- Hello.
My name is Long Zhentian.
Your Chinese is so good.
I am Feng Qiuhuang.
- Shang Zhitao.
- Hi.
Zhentian is my batchmate
from the university. He's Canadian.
His native languages
are English and French,
and he speaks really good Chinese.
I can tell.
You like playing LTK as a foreigner?
So-so. The third best player in the world.
I'm actually looking for a Chinese tutor
to practice my speaking skills.
You're looking for a Chinese tutor?
What a coincidence.
Tao is looking for an English tutor.
You two can exchange numbers
and study with one another.
Wonderful. Give me a call.
Type your number.
What's your goal
for your English proficiency?
As good as your Chinese proficiency.
Then, you'll have to work hard.
You too.
All right. Enough serious talk.
- Deal the cards now.
- Deal the cards.
Here. Take this.
Come in.
Boss. I'm leaving now.
It's Friday today.
You don't live to work.
It's only 7 p.m.
But it's the weekend now.
A normal person would already
be queuing at a hot pot restaurant.
Just go.
Happy weekend.
Do go home early.
It seems Yuanzhu has been charmed.
- Allow me.
- Mince your words now.
- Thanks.
- If Sun gets mad,
he'll kill your character off.
Sun has a good temper. He won't kill you.
You don't know this.
Back then, our boss stole his code
and even tried to pin
the blame on him and fire him.
And he just flipped the table.
I didn't know
you could be this aggressive.
You're always so even-tempered.
That guy must have been very awful
to make you this angry.
Guess what happened next?
That jerk couldn't understand
the logic behind Zhu's code.
There was a bug, and he couldn't fix it.
So he came crawling back
and begged Zhu to come back.
You should've seen the face of that loser.
Well, Zhu, what did you tell him?
I told him that at work,
nothing was a given.
No one should think that
they are above everyone else.
Without the effort of the employees,
no matter how big the company is,
it's just an empty shell.
Don't lie.
What you wanted to say was…
Screw you!
Come. Carry on.
- Come.
- It's your turn now.
I use Invasion of Nanman.
- I don't have any strike cards.
- Strike cards.
I don't have any strike cards.
I still have one, Tao.
Sun Yu. They are having an event here.
Where are you?
Come now. Quick.
Okay. Sure. I'll be there.
Okay.
Sorry, guys.
My boss told me
something happened at the event.
I need to head back to fix it.
I have to go now.
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
My company can't live without me.
I have to go now.
- Bye.
- Take care.
It's hard to get a ride here.
I'll drive you out.
- Okay.
- Let's go.
Come.
It's getting late.
Let's head back as well.
- Okay.
We'll hang out another time.
- See you.
- Bye.
- We'll go as well.
Are you free later?
Do you have time?
Maybe we can have our first session today?
Really?
Yes.
Should we go somewhere else?
- Sure.
- Okay.
Let me pack this up.
‪Hello.
Where are you?
About to drive home.
Song Qiuhan and Chen Kuannian are back.
Let's grab a drink today.
- Their bar is launching today.
- No, thanks.
Dude. It's the weekend.
Are you really going to stay at home
and talk to your fish?
That's my time with my pet.
Fine.
If I cannot convince you,
the others will call you anyway.
Find a way to turn them down then.
Hanging up.
This is the place.
It's new.
I heard there's
a special performance tonight.
It's crowded.
Drifters in Beijing all gather here.
It's the culture.
The culture.
This is the soul of Beijing.
You work during the day.
You live at night.
It is quite different.
When I first came to Beijing,
I could not speak a word of Chinese.
I learned it all from friends
I made in bars.
It's the same with English.
You can't rely on textbooks alone.
You must come here
and be immersed
in a real language environment.
Let me teach you how to order a drink.
Qiuhan.
How much did you invest in this place?
- How much?
- Chen Kuannian invested in it as well.
- We're in it together.
- What do you think?
I invested in it too.
You two sure are rich.
It is good.
This place is not bad, right?
- But your decor is…
- Decor is…
The location is good.
Is that you, Mr. Luan?
Your fish finally let you out?
Luan Nian?
Let him out?
I bet his fish is sick of him,
so it kicked him out.
Since you're here,
then we must have a drink.
It's on you.
Consider it your gift for my opening day.
Don't. I just paid it.
As you should.
- Come.
Hello.
You need to work on your pronunciation.
Yes.
You said two martinis ten times.
That's 20 martinis.
Long Zhentian. We'll split the bill.
Okay.
Then, I'll teach you more things today.
What do you want to learn?
I want to learn how to politely
turn down drinks during a business dinner.
But…
You're Chinese,
and you work in advertising.
How are you supposed
to close deals without drinking?
Even you say so.
So, how do I learn to hold my drinks?
Just drink more.
- Really?
- Yes.
Maybe recite some Chinese poems or idioms.
It'll be even better.
Quick. Teach me something.
What makes you drunk
is not liquor, but desires.
But sorrows feel even more bitter
when you drown them with liquor.
Yes. Cheers.
Cheers.
Luke. We haven't heard you sing in years.
It's our opening day today.
Sing for us.
No way.
Don't say no.
Everyone is here.
It's our bar.
You won't embarrass yourself.
No.
You're still the same
as when you were at school.
You don't play along.
Just get off your pedestal
and let us enjoy your talent.
Will I get paid?
- I…
- Yes.
When we were studying…
- How much was it again?
- 500 yuan.
- Yes, 500 yuan.
I'll pay you ten times that amount. No.
If you can sing until morning,
I'll give this bar to you.
You might as well earn it.
- Seriously?
- Here he goes.
He's doing it.
Gosh!
Yes!
Do you think Luan Nian
is quite distracted today?
What is he looking at?
Impossible.
Who is this beauty who earns his gaze?
I think I know that girl.
- Which one?
Did he find a new girlfriend?
No way.
Why didn't he tell us?
Anyway, I have to use the toilet.
Luan Nian!
Luan Nian?
Are you okay?
- Where did he go?
- Who?
The singer.
Luke.
Sorry, but…
No one was singing.
Are you drunk?
Can you continue?
A toast to music.
A toast to friends.
A toast to good food.
A toast to stupid people.
I can't drink anymore.
I want to go home.
- Not bad, Luan Nian.
- You still have it.
Pay up.
Foot the bill now.
I asked you to sing until morning,
not just one song.
Thank you.
Hey, hey.
Hey, calm down. Calm down.
What's happening?
What are you doing?
- Easy now.
- What's going on?
- Girlfriend?
- Luke.
It's you.
Are you really her tutor?
- Cheers.
- Yes.
Private English tutor.
Let's go.
No.
She hasn't finished her work.
It's the weekend.
What work?
Are you done with the summary report?
And here you are, at a bar.
Summary report?
Not done yet.
Can you teach me?
Sure.
I'll drive you home.
Wow.
Easy now. Come.
- They are working.
- I'll be going now.
- Come. Let's drink.
- Let's drink.
- Bye.
- Come. Let's drink.
Let's drink.
- Stand straight.
I'll buy some water to sober you up.
Stand straight!
You're doing this on purpose, aren't you?
How can you be this handsome
when you're angry?
Stop it.
What?
They say you are very mean,
but I don't think so.
You just have a duck bill.
A duck bill. You know what?
A duck bill is like this.
Useless Lumi.
Look.
Like this.
You keep appearing in my dreams.
What happened in the dream?
I…
I was scolding you.
You wish. Shang Zhitao.
It's time for you to lose weight
because you're about to break my arms.
Luan Nian!
My dad tells me to eat more.
Otherwise, a strong gust of wind
will blow me away.
Tell your father not to worry
because you have aced that task.
Is your dad good to you?
Is your dad not good to you?
Does he know you're stupid?
You're drinking
when your ankle is barely healed.
Do not underestimate me.
I am slow,
but every step I take is very real.
See?
- Did you see it?
- Yes.
Let me show you.
Yes, very real. Come.
Mister. To Tiantong Dongyuan.
To Tiantongyuan.
SHANG ZHITAO
SUN YU
TIANTONG DONGYUAN, SECTION 1
Over there.
Sixty what?
6…
602.
Sunflower.
The one with a sunflower.
Sit down.
I am not drunk.
Who is it?
Who are you?
Crazy.
Sun Yu.
Sun Yu!
Stop it, or I'll call the police.
Where is your home?
I don't know.
I want to sleep.
Does it still hurt?
No.
I got this when I was saving you.
Back in ancient times…
You'd have to marry me.
Come home with me.
You're quite mature when it comes to love.
You must think
I'm an irresponsible playboy.
Isn't an amicable separation
what breaking up is all about?
I knew it.
When you relax,
your brain will betray you.
Instead of finding ways
to gain a footing at work,
I think of useless things like this.